Let's get really real, real, real now, okay?
For example, let's say you have joined a
company, you're a data engineer.
Now you're in a data engineering team of Lyft Company.
Lyft is a ride share company in the us similar to Uber,
and you're assigned to this brand new
project by your manager.
So what's this project all about?
Lyft Company's business
team data analysts wanna work on optimizing their revenue
and driver operations for the New York City rides.
So that's the high level goal Now.
So what's gonna happen next is you and your manager
and the business data analyst team are gonna get together in
a meeting and discuss the goals of the project.
So the outcome of meeting is gonna be a few things in the
meeting the business team says to you
and a manager that we really need your help.
The data engineering team's help
in optimizing the revenue and driver operations.
And for that we have identified, we have a real data source,
and that is the New York City's Taxi
and Limo scene Commission data.
They tell you that this data gets published on the
NYC dot government site around this portal.
If you scroll down below, if you go to download data
and then go to the raw data
and then trip record data,
you'll see there are some data sets here for yellow trips,
green trips, FHE, and high volume FHE here.
And if we scroll down, you will see you have
a ton of data here.
And what they ask you is that they all
actually start analyzing this data.
The high volume fhv data.
If you click on this, so here you have data for Uber, Lyft,
via and June, four different companies.
And Lyft business team is interested in
actually analyzing this data.
It has information about the pickup, the drop off, daytime,
the location IDs, the trip miles, the trip time,
the base passenger for a lot more, in fact,
which can help the lift companies business team to
optimize their revenue and driver operations.
When you go back and they tell you that we go
to start analyzing with at least one file first,
they wanna actually view the data,
they wanna see the data, okay?
And the data is actually in Parquet format.
So the source of the data is identified.
Now, the next step that they want help is
with getting them access to this data so
that they can really do some analysis.
But this is a Parquet file.
I mean, if you download, if you click on this,
you can download the file, but you cannot open that.
It's a Parquet, it's a format.
It's not as Excel sheet or CSV.
So the outcome of the meeting was that
the source status is identified,
and the next action item for you is to help them get access
to that data so that they can analyze
and define the requirements
for your data engineering project.